So friends, ICICI Psalm Life Insurance
Company has disclosed its quarter 4 numbers.
So let's see
what the numbers are for Quarter 4. The
data here is in lakhs.  I'm
telling you in the cross.  So, if we
talk about the last quarter, the
total income of the company in the last quarter was Rs 22302
crore.  If we talk about last year, it was
around Rs 15637 crore, whereas if we look at it now,
you can see it falling to Rs 3782 crore.  So if you
look here,
you will see a big decline in the total income of the company.  It goes on
quarterly basis every year or two.
So here too you saw a big decline.
But remember
why the total income has fallen?  Because in this quarter the
company has suffered a lot of losses through investments.  The
company has suffered a loss of Rs 16302 crore through investment
in this quarter.  Whereas last year there was a
loss of about Rs 94 crore.  Whereas
in the last quarter there was a profit of Rs 10,745 crore.
Due to which you are seeing less total income of the company.
However, all these things do
not hold much importance.  Basically, in all the life
insurance companies, be it LIC
, HDFC Life or ICICI,
this total income is not very important.
What is most important?  The most important factor is
your APE i.e. Annualized Premium
Equivalent.  If we look at this, the
APE of the company last year was around Rs
crore.  Talking about the last quarter, the
company's profit in the last quarter was Rs 24
crore.  Whereas if we look at this quarter, the
APE of the company will be
seen going up to Rs 3614 crore.  So if we
look here and see the APE of the company,
you can see it increasing slightly year after year.  There
is a rise of around 3%.   If we
go on a quarterly basis, you would have seen a huge increase.
However, the market
also believed the same.  The market was estimated to be Rs 3616 crore.  The
APE of the company is what you
can see coming.  So you
can say that you are
able to see the company's APE inline.  Let us
see what the company's expenses are.
So see, in the last quarter the
company had spent Rs 2233 crore.  Last
year it was ₹15343 crore, whereas in this quarter
you will see the company spending ₹2150 crore.
So if we look at the expenses,
you are seeing very less expenses and the
reason behind the reduction in expenses
is the liability of the company because if we look at the liability,
here in the name of change in law actual
liability, the company has got a profit of Rs 14419 crore
in this quarter
due to which you are seeing very less expenses.
Let us see what the net profit of the company is.
So see,
in the last quarter the company was
in profit of Rs 387 crore.  Last year it was around Rs 385 crore,
whereas if you look at it now, you can see the company's profit
going up to Rs 623 crore.
So, if we go year after year,
you are seeing a huge increase in the profits of the company every year.
You can expect a
jump of around 60%.  If we look at the company's profits on a
yearly or quarterly basis,
here too
you can see a jump of around 60%.  So let's look
inside the company's profits.
You are going to see a big jump.  So
you are seeing good profits.
Remember, the company has
also announced a dividend of ₹1.65
in this quarter.  Whereas last year the
company had given a dividend of 0.85.  So if you
look at the dividend, you are seeing it doubling every year.
And
if you look at the EPS of the company, it was 2.68 in the last quarter and
2.67 last year, whereas if you look at it now, it has
increased to 4.31 and the
company has not mentioned anything about NPA here.
So if seen overall, the
numbers seem fine.  Meaning, we
cannot call it a bad number.  However, you have
seen very little total income.  But the total
income does not increase.  What is important is the
company's APE Annualized Premium
Equivalent. If you look at it, you can
see it increasing by 3% year after year.  It is in line.  It is as much as the
market had anticipated.
See profit increased by 60%.
Dividend has also been given.  So the numbers
look fine.  Let's see
how it reacts to the market.  If you like the video then please
like it.  Also,
please subscribe to the channel.